Guide to the Margaret Wylie papers, 1926-1963.
Wylie, Margaret papers, 1926-1963.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Margaret Wylie papers, 1926-1963.
23-13-491
Margaret Wylie, 1889-1964.
ca. 54.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, course materials, other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, course outlines, trip reports, questionnaires, memoranda and other papers deriving from Dr. Wylie's professional work in child development and family studies, including twin studies and the Cornell child study clubs; includes some personal correspondence, as with Flora Rose.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Child Development and Family Relationships, Cornell University. Dr. Wylie established the extension program in Family Life.
Margaret Wylie earned her bachelor's, master's, and doctorate degrees from the University of Michigan. She arrived at the College of Home Economics in 1925 and for three years she initiated extension institutes and follow-up programs in eight counties in New York State. She left Cornell to complete her Ph.D. in psychology and retuned in 1930 and remained until 1957. She was responsible for developing child study clubs and establishing Cornell's extension program in family life.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, course outlines, trip reports, questionnaires, memoranda and other papers deriving from Dr. Wylie's professional work in child development and family studies, including twin studies and the Cornell child study clubs; includes some personal correspondence, as with Flora Rose.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wylie, Margaret, 1889-1964.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Home Economics.
Subjects:
Family--Study and teaching.; Child development--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Cornell Study Groups
Albany County
Allegany County
Broome County
Buffalo County
Cattaraugus County
Cayuga County
Chatauqua County
Chemung County
Chenango County
Clinton County
Columbia County
Cortland County
Delaware County
Dutchess County
Erie and Buffalo County
Franklin County
Fulton County
Genesee County
Green County
Herkimer County
Jefferson County
Lewis County
Livingston County
Madison County
Monroe County and Rochester
Montgomery County
Nassau County
Niagara County
Oneida County
Onondaga County and Syracuse
Ontario County
Orange County
Orleans County
Oswego County
Ostego County
Rensselaer County
Rockland County
St. Lawrence County
Saratoga County
Schenectady County
Schoharie County
Schuyler County
Seneca County
Steuben County
Suffolk County
Sullivan County
Tioga County
Tompkins County
Ulster County
Warren County
Washington County
Wayne County
Westchester County
Wyoming County
Yates County
Series II. Subject Files, Correspondence, Booklets, and Questionnaires
RELATED MATERIALS
Consists of collections #23-13-648, #23-13-675, and #23-13-1586.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Cornell Study Clubs
  - Albany County
    - Albany County - Albany, Delmar, Loudinville, Slingerland, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Albany County - Albany, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Cyrus Crounse, Jr., Albany, NY, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, Dept. of Family Life, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, Dept. of Family Life, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Home Bureau, 1943-1944 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Allegany County
    - Allegany County: Belmont, NY, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1932-1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Miss Teresa M. Duggan, Friendship, NY, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Emma Harris, Belmont Child Study Club, 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Home Bureau unit meetings, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, Court House, Belmont, NY, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Broome County
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1930-1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Ann Phillips Duncan, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Vestal Family Life Study Club, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Doris Davern, Whitney Point, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Walter Farrell, Johnson City, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. L.A. Osborn, Binghamton, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. Katherine Doyle, Home Demonstration Agent -- Court House, Binghamton, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Home Bureau, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Vestal Study Club, Mrs. Clarence Hill, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Chenango Bridge, Mrs. Ivan Stanton, R.D. #4, Binghamton, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Buffalo County
    - Untitled, 1930-1933 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Daniel Lanning, Harris Hill, Wildwood Drive, Williamsville, NY, 1942-1945 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Peter Murrett, 169 Wardman Rd., Kenmore, NY, County Leader, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Adolescence," outline, Buffalo group (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Eaton, Leadership I, Buffalo, NY, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Eaton, Leadership II, Buffalo, NY (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. Eaton, County Leader, Leadership III, Buffalo, NY (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Abbott Road, Buffalo - Mrs. Edwin Klas, 93 Meridian St., 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Jefferson-Humboldt, Buffalo - Mrs. Bert E. Flanagan, 155 Ledge Road, Akron, NY, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Bailey Genesee Gr. - Mrs. Robert Gearey, 46 Central Bldv. Buffalo 11, NY, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Jack and Jill, Buffalo - Mrs. F.R. Cowan, 75 Eiseman Ave., Kenmore 17, NY, 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. C.J. Tyner, 24 La Salle, Kenmore, NY, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. George C. Kratzer, 140 Wardman, Buffalo, NY, Ken Del, 1940-1943 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. George C. Kratzer, 140 Wardman, Buffalo, NY, 1942-1943 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Peter Murrett, 169 Wardman Rd., Kenmore, NY, Ken Del, 1942-1944 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. W. Lynch, 126 Lincoln, Buffalo, NY, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Mrs. James Carhart, 44 Kenwood Rd., Kenmore, NY, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Mrs. R.C. Wilson, 51 Knowlton, Kenmore, NY, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. John F. Costello, 159 E. Hazeltine Ave., Kenmore, NY, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Raymond Nauth, 184 Highgate Ave., Buffalo, NY, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Mrs. Charles Wiggle, 126 Berkshire, Buffalo, NY; Kers Group II, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Kensington II, Chairman, Buffalo, NY, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Kensington No. I, 248 Oakmont, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Buffalo, Newcomer Mothers Club - Mrs. A.J. Sterner, 234 Knowlton, Kenmore, NY, 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Mrs. Harry York, 795 Glenwood, Buffalo, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - North Oak Study Group - Mrs. Harry Atkins, 88 Urban St., Buffalo 11, 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Mrs. G. Howard Chappell, 584 Tacoma Ave., Buffalo; Park School 1st grade (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Park School Group - Mrs. Arthur Maddigan, 76 Soldiers Place, Buffalo, 1942-1944 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Mrs. Carl Ponder, 44 Ruchinvole St., Buffalo, 1940-1943 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Riverside Study Club, Mrs. Daniel McCarthy, 135 Crowley Ave., Buffalo, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Mrs. James P. Cotter, 177 Choate St., Buffalo, 1940-1943 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Bennett Study Club, Florence Taylor, Kenmore, NY, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Charles T. Ryan, 234 Englewood Ave., Buffalo, 1941-1943 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - University Heights Study Club - Mrs. James Stewart, Ch., 40 W. Northrup, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Mrs. O. Christie, 180 Merrimac, Buffalo, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Mrs. Jack Roach, 178 Lisbon, Buffalo, NY, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Westminster Family Life - Mrs. Florence Spring, 47 Welmont Pl., Buffalo, 1943-1944 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Mrs. Howard A. Gibson, 423 Tremont Ave., Kenmore, NY, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Cattaraugus County
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Helen Whiting, Delavan, NY, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Frances Graham, 1932-1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Edith Anderson, Olean, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. A. Aust, Otto, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mrs. J.E. Fitzpatrick, Ellicottville, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Marjorie Smith, Cattaraugus, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Sadie Tisch, Gowanda, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. D.C. Northrup, Ellicottville, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. G.A. Bump, West Valley (Riceville Home Bureau), 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. Chester Ehman, West Valley, 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. Alfred Mercer, Ellicottville, 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. Luella Canfield, Ellicottville, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. Shirley Persons, Delavan, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Lily Schrader, Hinsdale, NY, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. John F. Kane, Olean, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. M. Steffenhagen, West Valley, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Mrs. Maude Button, Olean, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Mrs. Mabelle Holmes, Yorkshire, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. J.W. Nosal, Salamanca, NY, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Frances M. Graham, 27 Maple St., Salamanca, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Home Bureau reports, etc., 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - County Leader, Mrs. Louise W.D. Bump, West Valley, NY, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Mrs. Olga Zeffers, West Valley, NY, 1941-1944 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Mrs. Mary Roberson, Machias, NY, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Cayuga County
    - ???, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1932-1940 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. H.B. Wyckoff, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Harold Kallstrom, Moravia, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. Herbert MaDann, Union Springs, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Henry Gray, Jr., Aurora, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. Paul Bresnan, Scipio Center, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - King Ferry Mother's Club, Mrs. C.F. Minard, King Ferry, NY, 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material (EMPTY FOLDER), 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth Wiegand, 300 P.O. Bldg., Auburn, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - King Ferry Study Club, Chmn, Mrs. Ruth Howland, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Chautauqua County
    - Chautauqua County - Jamestown, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. Mary Charvet, Fredonia, NY (Lamberton), 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Laura Lee Britz, Fredonia, 1935-1940 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. L. Magnuson, Jamestown, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Edwin Sharp, Jamestown, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Clarence Carlson, Jamestown, 1931-1940 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Mrs. Fred Buffington, Jamestown, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Theo Hewes, Mayville, NY (Stedman Club), 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Frank Taylor, Silver Creek, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. Edith Nasca, Fredonia (Laona Club), 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Joseph Dykes, Fredonia Club, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. Gertrude Bundholm, Mayville, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. Winifred Campbell, Cassadaga, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Chautauqua-Stedman Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Ben Pringle (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. Howard Lyon, Falcones, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Cassadaga Family Life Study Club, Mrs. Agnes Dorman, Cassadaga, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Ellington Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Gertrude Anderson, 1938-1940 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Ralph Keopka, Westfield, 1933-1934 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. Marcella Armstron, Westfield, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Mrs. Julia Beckman, Westfield, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Forestville Family Life Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Louis DeBello, 1930-1939 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. Elinor Barmore, Gerry, NY, 1936-1940 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Marjorie Bunting Bush, 1931-1932 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Jamestown, NY, 1930-1931 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Miss Virginia Brewster, Home Demonstration Agent, Jamestown, NY, 1932-1940 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Mr. Entorf's materials, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Blockville Pre-School Circle, Chairman Mrs. Daphne Morrison, Ashville, NY, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Mrs. Francis Peterson, Ashville, 1936-1937 (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Mrs. Asa Cheney, Bemies Point, NY, 1931-1932 (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Mrs. William Ebert, Dunkirk, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - S. Virginia Brewster, Home Demonstration Agent, Federal Bldg., Jamestown, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Home Bureau, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Gerry Child Study Club -- Gerry, NY, Chairman Lois Tolman, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Fredonia Child Study, Mrs. Frank Saqyer, 16 Barker, 1941-1944 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Fredonia Family Life Study Club, Mrs. Melville Evorts, Fredonia, NY, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Mrs. Helen Karl, R.F.D. #1, Fredonia, NY, 1940-1942 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Ellington Family Life Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Hattie McKee, 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Dunkirk Family Life Study Club, Chairman Mrs. W. Nopper, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Westfield Child Study, Mrs. Joe Ricketts, 22 Cottage St., Westfield, 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 50)
  - Chemung County
    - Chemung County - Elmira, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Chemung County - Elmira, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Chemung County: Elmira, NY, 1930-1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Chemung County: Elmira, NY, 1930-1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Miss G. Dorothy Williams, Elmira, NY, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. B. Gehrig, Elmira, NY (Ruby Green Smith study club), 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. Charles MacDougall, Horseheads, NY, 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. Eva Mathews, Horseheads, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. Floyd Strick, Elmira, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. William Wigsten, Horseheads, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Henry Young, Elmira Heights, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. Gladys Isaacs, Elmira Heights, NY, 1937-1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Marian May, East Elmira Study Club, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Chenango County
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Mrs. Charles Dunkle, Norwich, NY, 1934-3 5 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Sherburne, NY, study club, 1934-1936 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Mrs. S.J. Angell, Mt. Upton, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Mrs. Elsie Lamb, South Otselic, NY, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Mrs. Mary Lottridge, North Norwich, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Mrs. Rockwood's material, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Mrs. Kenneth Sexton, Earlville, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Tunnel, NY, study club, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Mrs. J.R. Hoyt, New Berlin, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Home Bureau unit meetings, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. George Brooks, Chenango Cty. Adult Study Club, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Mrs. Philip Close, Earlville study club, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Mrs. Walter Cosens, N. Norwich Family Life Study Club, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Rev. Guy Crawford, S. Otselic Adult Study Club, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Mrs. Ralph Cumber, Norwich, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Mrs. James Faulkner, Sherburne Family Life Study Club, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Mrs. R. Garrison, Bainbridge, NY, Middle Years Study Club, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Mrs. Ivan Gilliand, Smyrna, NY, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Mrs. Joseph Ricotta, South New Berlin, NY, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Mrs. Betsy Stanton, Norwich: The Woods Corners Club, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Mrs. Helen Utter, Oxford Family Life Study Club, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Mrs. Charlotte K. Runey, Home Demonstration Agent, 309 Federal Bldg., Elmira, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Home Bureau, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Oakwood Family Life Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Gladys Isaacs, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Veteran Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Charles MacDougall, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "Sex in Character Education," Miss Ethel Phillips, Elmira, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Home Bureau Units, reports, etc., 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Norwich Child Study Club, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Norwich Adult Study Club, 1940-1943 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. W.A. Cosens, Norwich, NY, 1940-1942 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Child Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Archie Gilland, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Oxford Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Richard DeLong, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Smyrna Child Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Robert Peters, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Clinton County
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Florence Stachpole, Plattsburg, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Peru Study Club, Mrs. Herbert Sanders, Peru, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Wednesday Study Club, Mrs. Donald Studholme, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Peru Family Life Study Club, Mrs. H. Sanders, Jr., 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Home Bureau unit meetings, 1940-1942 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Chazy Child Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Laura Kay, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Columbia County
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cortland County
    - Cortland County, Cortland, NY, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Mae E. Phalen, Marathon, NY, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Preble Child Study Club, Preble, NY, 1931-1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Robert Usher, Cortland County Leader, 1931-1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Marjorie Creal, Homer, NY, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, 1934-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. A.B. Knapp, Marathon, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Norton Knapp, Little York, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. Karl Muller, Truxton, NY, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Rockwood' s material, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mr. Allan Bean, McGraw, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Mrs. F.L. Burnham, Little York, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. Mabel Carr, Willet, NY, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Mrs. H. Cordary, Homer, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Harry E. Curtis, Cuyler, NY ("45 Club"), 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Mr. Entorf's material, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Ira Garner, McGraw, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Mrs. Russell E. Hackett, Lapeer Child Study Club, Marathon, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Mrs. O.C. Pond, Marathon, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - East Homer Child Study Club, 1937-1940 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. Earl Pond, Virgil Group, Lambda Alpha Phi, 1937-1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Mrs. Aldelpha Seymour, Cortland, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Mrs. Freda Sternberg, Cincinnatus, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Cortland County reports of meetings in Home Bureau Units, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mrs. C. Dixon, Truxton Family Life Study Club, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mrs. Horace Button, Scott Road Child Study Club, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Preble Child Study, 1942-1944 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Scott Road Study Club, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Parent Improvement Study Club, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Chairman Mrs. Bessie Sherman, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Truxton Study Club, Chairman Mrs. Mary Comerford, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Virgil Child Study Club, Chairman Mrs. C.L. Dickinson, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Cortland, NY, Chairman Mrs. William MacDougall, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Dryden, NY, Chairman Mrs. Ida Dickinson, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Elizabeth J. Nisbet, Home Demonstration Agent, Court House, Cortland, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Home Bureau, 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Delaware County
    - Delaware County - Integrated County, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - 1931-1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Home Demonstration Agent, P.O. Bldg., Delhi, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Family Life Leaders, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Home Bureau, Exec. Com. Sponsor, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Franklin Mothers Club, Robert Howland, Franklin, NY, 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Dutchess County
    - Prof. M. Entorf's Material (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Erie County and Buffalo
    - Erie County - Buffalo, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Mrs. James T. Grey, Clarence, NY study club, 1931-1932 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mrs. Lyle Brown, Gowanda, NY study club, 1 932- 1 938 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Mrs. Rockwoods's material, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mrs. S. B. McAllister, Jr., Hamburg, NY study club, 1935-1940 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Conrad Schneider, Hamburg, NY study club, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Sadie Belle Cornelius, Hamburg, NY, 1937-1940 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Mr. Entorf, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Henry W. Fleischman, East Aurora, 1931-1935 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Mrs. C.E. Burns, Clarence, NY, 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Mrs. Etoile Britt, Gowanda: Collins Center, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Mrs. Mary Clark, Elma, NY, 1934-1936 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Mrs. Eldon Mook, Clarence, NY, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Mrs. Lewis Davis, Clarence Center, 1935-1940 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Mrs. Ella Vance, Collins, NY, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Mrs. Daniel L. Volker, Eden, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Mrs. M. Becker, Collins Center, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Mrs. F. Fineour, Collins Center, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Mrs. H.L. Jensen, East Aurora, 1936-1939 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Mrs. Theodore Zittle, East Aurora, 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Mrs. Leonard Mowry, Kenmore, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Mrs. Frank Patridge, Kenwood, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Mrs. E.J. Beuther, Buffalo, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Mrs. George Loescher, Buffalo, 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Mrs. Roy Stanfield, Buffalo, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Mrs. Roy Stanfield, South Gunning Sorority Group, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Mrs. Matthews, Buffalo Presbyterian Church, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Mrs. C.E. Meinecke, Westminster group, 1931-1939 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Mrs. Walter Gibbs, Three Bears Nursery School, 1933-1937 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Mrs. Lottie Levi, Buffalo, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 68)